Guide to the National Student Christian Federation Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Commission on World Mission, Series IV
  - Speaking Engagements of C. Alton Robertson
    - Department of Campus Christian Life Conference of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S., Montreat, North Carolina. Includes speech "The Mood of the Campus.", August, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 311)
    - YMCA/YWCA Student Conference, Estes Park, Colorado, September 5-12, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 312)
    - Consultant for Consultation of World Mission, Presbyterian Church in the U.S., Montreat, North Carolina, October 13-19, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 313)
    - School of Mission Program, Auburn, Alabama, January 13-15, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 314)
    - Methodist Student Movement Regional Conferences, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 315)
    - Florida Methodist Student Movement State Conference, Leesburg, Florida, February 21-23, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 316)
    - Vocational Day at Brooklyn College, April 29, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 317)
    - South Central Regional Conference of the Methodist Student Movement, Wilburton, Oklahoma, August 23-25, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 318)
    - Tenth Triennial Assembly of United Church Women, Kansas City, Missouri. C. Alton Robertson was in charge of a panorama. Panorama script included., October 1964 (Box 26, Folder 319)
    - Third Annual Eastern Regional Migrant Ministry Conference, Washington, D.C. C. Alton Robertson was a consultant, March 15-19, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 319a)
    - Forum at Davis and Elkins College, Elkins, West Virginia, March 17-18, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 320)
- Committee on the Interseminary Movement, Series V
  These records are arranged into two subseries: Administrative Records and NCCC Faith and Order Commission. The Administrative Records contain three subseries: Correspondence, Finances, and General Records. All content arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Administrative Records
    - Correspondence
      - Re. articles for The Interseminarian journal, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 321)
      - Bridston, Keith, 1961-1963 (Box 26, Folder 322)
      - Canadian student Christian movement, 1961-1963 (Box 26, Folder 323)
      - Christian Century, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 324)
      - Re. committee meetings, 1960-1961 (Box 26, Folder 325)
      - Re. ecumenism, 1957, 1960-1961 (Box 26, Folder 326)
      - General, 1962-1963 (Box 26, Folder 327)
      - Re. graduate student pilot project, 1961-1962 (Box 26, Folder 328)
      - Henderson, William, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 329)
      - Re. Interseminary Movement faculty advisors, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 330)
      - Re. finances, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 331)
      - Inter-office, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 332)
      - Re. The Intercollegian publication, 1961-1963 (Box 27, Folder 333)
      - Re. The Interseminarian journal, 1960-1963 (Box 27, Folder 334)
      - Interseminary Movement Regional Faculty Directors, 1961-1962 (Box 27, Folder 335)
      - Kentucky-Tennessee Interseminary region, 1959-1963 (Box 27, Folder 336)
      - Mid-Atlantic Interseminary region, 1959-1963 (Box 27, Folder 337)
      - Midwest Interseminary region, 1959-1963 (Box 27, Folder 338)
      - Miscellaneous, 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 339)
      - Re. NCCC meeting in Kansas City, Missouri, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 340)
      - Re. NSCF, 1960-1962 (Box 27, Folder 341)
      - Nelson, J. Robert, 1961-1963 (Box 27, Folder 342)
      - New England Interseminary region, 1959-1963 (Box 27, Folder 343)
      - Ohio Interseminary region, 1959-1963 (Box 27, Folder 344)
      - Re. possible move of Interseminary National offices to Chicago, 1961-1962 (Box 28, Folder 345)
      - Re. postponement of Interseminary Movement Triennial Conference, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 346)
      - Re. Professors of Ecumenics, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 347)
      - Re. publications includes drafts, 1960-1961 (Box 28, Folder 348)
      - Quillian, Joseph (Dean of Perkins Theological School, Southern Methodist University, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 349)
      - Re. regional Interseminary groups, 1960-1963 (Box 28, Folder 350)
      - Requests for information, 1961-1963 (Box 28, Folder 351)
      - Seminary addresses and numbers, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 352)
      - Southeastern Interseminary region, 1959-1963 (Box 28, Folder 353)
      - Southwestern Interseminary region, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 354)
      - Southwest Interseminary region, 1961-1963 (Box 28, Folder 355)
      - Re. Study Commission tasked to study role of ISM, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 356)
      - Taylor, Charles (American Association of Theological Schools), 1961-1963 (Box 28, Folder 357)
      - Re. textbook for Indian students, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 358)
      - Re. theological education, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 359)
      - Tobias, Robert, 1961-1962 (Box 29, Folder 360)
      - Re. traveling international student, Abraham Viljoen. Includes reports., 1963 (Box 29, Folder 361)
      - Re. Triennial study materials, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 362)
      - Wagoner, Walter, 1962 (Box 29, Folder 363)
      - Western Interseminary region, 1959-1963 (Box 29, Folder 364)
      - Will, James, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 365)
      - Correspondence of William Lovell (Acting NSCF General Secretary), 1962 (Box 29, Folder 366)
      - Re. William Crews leaving Interseminary Movement and preplanning for Triennial Conference, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 367)
    - Finances
      - Budget and finance information, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 368)
      - Commingled fund, 1962 (Box 29, Folder 369)
      - Contributions, 1962-1963 (Box 29, Folder 370)
      - Correspondence re. deficit, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 371)
      - Expenditures and askings, 1961-1962 (Box 29, Folder 372)
      - Expenditures and askings, 1962-1963 (Box 29, Folder 373)
      - Fundraising letters, 1960-1962 (Box 29, Folder 374)
      - Memos re. CISM budget, 1953-1960 (Box 30, Folder 375)
      - Minutes, 1961-1963 (Box 30, Folder 376)
      - Scholarship requests and scholarships for African Theological students, 1960-1961 (Box 30, Folder 377)
    - General Records
      - American Association of Theology Schools reports, 1961-1962 (Box 30, Folder 378)
      - American Association of Theology Schools reports, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 379)
      - Appointments to NSCF committees, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 380)
      - Articles and journals collected, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 381)
      - Church Union Seminar, Christian Theological Seminary, Indiana, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 382)
      - Church Union Seminar: Papers, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 383)
      - Closing of the Interseminary National Office, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 384)
      - Consultation on the future of the Interseminary, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 385)
      - Consultation on the future of the Interseminary: Drafts and notes, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 386)
      - Directory and mailing lists, 1961-1964 (Box 31, Folder 387)
      - Documents sent to Interseminary Movement regional groups including brochures and promotional materials, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 388)
      - Drafts of regional Interseminary Movement profiles, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 389)
      - Ecumenical Institute in Bossey, Switzerland, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 390)
      - General Assembly minutes, 1960-1963 (Box 31, Folder 391)
      - Graduate work with medical students, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 392)
      - Historical publications including 65 Years in the Seminaries: a History of the Interseminary Movement and Church in the World: the Story of the North American Interseminary Conference, 1946, 1947, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 393)
      - Information about the functions of the Interseminary Movement, 1962-1963 (Box 31, Folder 394)
      - Interseminary Publications Committee minutes, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 395)
      - Letter re. representation on the CISM, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 396)
      - Meeting agendas and documents, January 5-6, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 397)
      - Meeting agenda and report from Traveling Secretary, Abraham Viljuen, January 6-7, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 398)
      - Meeting agenda, minutes, and notes, January 5, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 399)
      - Memos, 1959-1963 (Box 32, Folder 400)
      - Memos, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 401)
      - Minutes, 1960-1962 (Box 32, Folder 402)
      - Minutes, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 403)
      - Minutes and reports re. termination of the national office of the Committee of the Interseminary Movement, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 404)
      - NCCC: Memos, minutes, and newsletters, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 405)
      - NCCC: Memos, minutes, and newsletters, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 406)
      - Papers and reports (miscellaneous), 1961-1963 (Box 33, Folder 407)
      - Proposal for a Christianity and Politics Seminar, 1961-1962 (Box 32, Folder 408)
      - Publications collected, 1959-1961 (Box 32, Folder 409)
      - Publications from regional Interseminary groups. Includes Journal of the Interseminary Movement of the Southwest, 1958, 1962, undated (Box 33, Folder 410)
      - Reports re. CISM work, 1960-1963 (Box 33, Folder 411)
      - Reports to the General Assembly, 1960-1963 (Box 33, Folder 412)
      - Student Interracial Ministry: Letters, minutes, and reports, 1962 (Box 33, Folder 413)
      - Study Commission: Minutes, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 414)
      - Study Commission: Reports, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 415)
      - Study Commission: Reports, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 415a)
      - Theological Education: Papers and reports, 1961-1963 (Box 34, Folder 416)
  - NCCC Faith and Order Commission
    - Articles, 1960-1962 (Box 34, Folder 417)
    - Correspondence re. Faith and Order research, and CISM's relationship with NCCC's Faith and Order department, 1962-1963 (Box 34, Folder 418)
    - Correspondence re. Faith and Order Seminars, 1962-1963 (Box 34, Folder 419)
    - Correspondence re. possible publications on the faith and order theme, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 420)
    - Correspondence re. publishing of Fifty Years of Faith and Order by J. Robert Nelson, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 421)
    - Faith and Order documents for use by Seminary Faith and Order Seminary (Box 34, Folder 422)
    - Faith and Order documents use by Seminary Faith and Order Seminaries, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 423)
    - Memos, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 424)
    - Miscellaneous papers including "Ecumenics in the Seminary Curriculum: a Survey and Appraisal" by Walter Gallop, 1960-1963 (Box 34, Folder 425)
    - NCCC Department of Faith and Order: Minutes, papers, and reports, 1960-1962 (Box 34, Folder 426)
    - World Council of Churches: Faith and Order papers, 1956, 1958, 1960, undated (Box 35, Folder 427)
    - World Council of Churches: Memos and WCC Bulletin, 1958-1962 (Box 35, Folder 428)
- Civil Rights Committee and Activities, Series VI
  - American College Students and Racial Integration by L. Maynard Catchings (study guide), 1956 (Box 35, Folder 429)
  - Civil Rights Employment, and the Social Status of American Negroes by Harold L. Sheppard and Herbert E. Striner (book). Based on a report for the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights (Contract Number CCFR-66-5)., 1966 (Box 35, Folder 430)
  - Civil Rights Newsletter published by the Civil Rights Committee of Cornell United Religious Work including letter from Paul Gibbons, 1964 (Box 35, Folder 431)
  - Correspondence and address list for lawyers re. Legal Aid for those arrested at sit ins, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 432)
  - Correspondence, Rinker, Charles, 1964 (Box 35, Folder 433)
  - Correspondence, U.S. Senators re. Civil Rights Bill and Nuclear Test Ban, 1963 (Box 35, Folder 434)
  - Letters, including Reverend John Eddy's "Washington Diary" which is his account of the March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom, 1963 (Box 35, Folder 435)
  - Memo re. Civil Rights Bill, 1963 (Box 35, Folder 436)
  - NCCC Civil Right memos and reports. Includes report from July 4, 1963 demonstration at Gwynn Oak Amusement Park, Baltimore, Maryland (Box 35, Folder 437)
  - NSCF Information letters re. the sit in movement and guidelines for action on the Civil Rights Bill, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 438)
  - "Report on the Student Non-Violent Movement" by Jim Monsonis, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 439)
  - Reports and working papers presented at General Assemblies, 1960-1962 (Box 35, Folder 440)
  - "A Survey of the Southern Student Sit-In Movement and Nationwide Student Activity" by United States National Student Assembly, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 441)
  - Strategic Assignment Teams: Correspondence and reports, 1964-1965 (Box 35, Folder 442)
- World Student Christian Federation, Series VII
  Records in this series are divided into two subseries: General and NSCF WSCF Programs and Projects. Within the latter subseries is separated into two subseries by project. Records in the General subseries arranged alphabetically by subject while the files in the Program and Project are arranged chronologically by date.
  - General
    - Circular documents re. Life and Mission of the Church project, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 443)
    - Constitution and by laws, 1956, 1957 (Box 35, Folder 444)
    - Correspondence between Elizabeth Adler and Harry Smith re. Political Commission. Includes Political Commission circular documents., 1948, 1960-1961 (Box 36, Folder 445)
    - Correspondence re. visa clearance for Risto Lehtonen (North American WSCF Secretary), 1962-1963 (Box 36, Folder 446)
    - Correspondence re. funding for WSCF North American Secretary, 1963 (Box 36, Folder 447)
    - Correspondence between Leonard Clough and Elizabeth Adler, 1963-1966 (Box 36, Folder 448)
    - Correspondence re. WSCF finances and subscriptions, 1964-1966 (Box 36, Folder 449)
    - Ecumenical Strategy including "Excerpts from USA Survey for the WSCF Ecumenical Strategy Consultation", 1964 (Box 36, Folder 450)
    - Life and Mission of the Church: News clippings, paper, and report, 1956-1959, 1964 (Box 36, Folder 451)
    - Life and Mission of the Church: Papers and study outlines including "The Christian Community and the New Humanity in the University" by Dr. M. Richard Shaull, 1959, 1964 (Box 36, Folder 452)
    - Report of WSCF Second European Pastor's Conference, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 453)
    - Report of a Visit in behalf of WSCF to Federacion de Colgides Cristianos de Puerto Rico by Herluf Jensen, 1958 (Box 36, Folder 454)
    - WSCF Survey of U.S. Boards of Missions involvement in the University world, 1964 (Box 36, Folder 455)
    - WSCF Project to establish an ecumenical strategy in the academic world, 1963 (Box 36, Folder 456)
  - NSCF WSCF Programs and Projects
    - Canada/Cuba/USA Study and Work Program
      - Correspondence re. Canada/Cuba/USA work and study project, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 457)
      - Report of the International Work Study Project Canada/Cuba/USA, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 458)
    - Universal Day of Prayer
      - Correspondence, Kurtztown Publishing Company, 1958-1959 (Box 37, Folder 459)
      - Correspondence, Requests for Materials, 1958-1959 (Box 37, Folder 460)
      - Program materials, 1958-1961 (Box 37, Folder 461)
      - Correspondence, Kurtztown Publishing Company. Includes draft of program, 1959-1960 (Box 37, Folder 462)
      - Correspondence and program materials, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 463)
      - Correspondence and poster, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 464)
      - Correspondence and program materials, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 465)
      - Correspondence, news releases, and program materials, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 466)
      - Program materials, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 467)
      - Requests for materials, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 468)
      - Correspondence, Kurtztown Publishing Company. Includes drafts of program materials, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 469)
      - Mailing addresses, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 470)
      - News releases and program materials, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 471)
      - Office procedures and program materials, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 472)
      - Requests for information, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 473)
      - Program materials including brochures and flyers, 1963 (Box 38, Folder 474)
      - Memos and program materials, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 475)
- Program Committees, Series VIII
  Program Committees arranged in six series: Committee on Christian Peace Concerns, Commission on Ecumenical Studies and Strategy, Committee on Christian Work Among International Students, Committee on Program and Study Secretaries, Latin America Concerns Committee, and South Africa Concerns Committee. The Commission on Ecumenical Studies and Strategy is divided into two subseries: General Committee Records and Life and Mission of the Church Program. The Committee on Work Among International Students subseries divided into two subseries: General Committee Records and Ecumenical International Ministries. All records organized alphabetically by subject.
  - Committee on Christian Peace Concerns
    NSCF President Bruce Douglas requested the Commission on Christian Peace Concerns be formed in order to supervise NSCF's proposed relationship to Turn Toward Peace. In addition to participating in Turn Toward Peace activities, the commission created study packets regarding Christian peace concerns. Records in this subseries reflect this relationship as well as the Commission's perspective on peace issues including the Cuban Missile Crisis.
    - Cuban missile crisis. Includes telegram the NSCF sent to President Kennedy, and Kennedy's reply., 1962 (Box 38, Folder 476)
    - Fourth General Assembly minutes re. Working Party on Peace, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 477)
    - Letters and memos, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 478)
    - Paper: "The Christian Peace Concern" by Nancy Bancroft, January 1964 (Box 38, Folder 479)
    - Papers: "A Proposal for Consideration of Christian Peace Concern", "A Perspective for CCPC of NSCF", and "Statements for Discussion on Current Political Issues Bearing on Peace and International Affairs", 1964 (Box 38, Folder 480)
    - Report: All Christian Peace Assembly in Prague, Czechsolvakia by Brewster Kneen, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 481)
    - Report and documents for VI General Assembly and to the Central Committee, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 482)
    - Turn Toward Peace organization, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 483)
  - Commission on Ecumenical Studies and Strategy
    This commission replaced the Study Department of the USCC which was both a study department and an ecumenical advisory committee. This commission was responsible for preparing study materials for the Life and Mission of the Church project. Initially, the USCC Study Department and the CWM's Study Department were to be combines, but this did not occur. Instead the CESS was parallel with the Commission on World Mission's Study Department. The difference being that the latter was focused directly on missions while the CESS could take a broader direction. At the IV General Assembly in 1962, the CESS endorsed the formation of the Inter-Movement Council, called for the creation of a Committee of Program and Study Secretaries, and to discontinue their own committee as the former two would replace it entirely. The General Assembly adopted the recommendation. Records in this subseries contain correspondence, drafts of publications, meeting minutes, reports, and materials produced for the Life and Mission of the Church Project.
    - General Committee Records
      - Article: Crossroads: Can the Church by the Church by J. Robert Nelson, 1954 (Box 38, Folder 484)
      - Arts folder, 1959-1960 (Box 38, Folder 485)
      - Bible study documents and resources, 1957-196? (Box 38, Folder 486)
      - Bible study resources and study guides, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 487)
      - Bible study documents and resources, undated (Box 38, Folder 488)
      - Bibliographies, 1959, 1962, undated (Box 39, Folder 489)
      - Budget information, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 490)
      - Correspondence, Ecumenical Student Groups, 1957-1960 (Box 39, Folder 491)
      - Correspondence re. publishing and procurement of Alexander Miller's Faith and Learning, 1958-1960 (Box 39, Folder 492)
      - Correspondence re. appointments to CESS, meeting attendance, and goals, 1959-1960 (Box 39, Folder 493)
      - Correspondence re. Thomas Wieser's attendance at the Iowa Student Ecumenical Conference, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 494)
      - Correspondence re. Thomas Wieser's travel to Southern United States for WSCF LMC program, 1959 (Box 39, Folder 495)
      - Correspondence re. regional Bible Study Seminars, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 496)
      - Correspondence, drafts, and galley proofs re. LMC brochure World, Word, and Sacrament, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 497)
      - Draft of Calvin's Doctrine of the Last Supper by Finley Eversole, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 498)
      - Draft: Why I Believe? by Robert Harris Gearhart, undated (Box 39, Folder 499)
      - Draft: Study guide for Luke and Acts, undated (Box 39, Folder 500)
      - Interpretive statement on the NSCF's Commission of Ecumenical Studies and Strategy, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 501)
      - Literature requests, 1960-1962 (Box 39, Folder 502)
      - Memos and minutes, 1959-1961 (Box 39, Folder 503)
      - Memos and minutes, 1961-1962 (Box 39, Folder 504)
      - Pamphlets and papers re. Christianity in Higher Education, Missions, and International Affairs, [1939-1963] (Box 40, Folder 505)
      - Papers: Jesus Christ on the Campus by Thomas Wieser and Strausbourg Seminar Report on Evangelism, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 506)
      - Preparatory paper and Report of the Working Committee for Activation of a Commission on Ecumenical Studies, 1960 (Box 40, Folder 507)
      - Reports, general, 1958-1962 (Box 40, Folder 508)
      - Report on the consultation for "The Meaning of Unity for the Life and Mission of the Student Christian Movement", 1958 (Box 40, Folder 509)
      - Study Guides including The Brokenness and Unity of the Church in the New Testament and A Study Guide for Spotlight on the College Student, undated (Box 40, Folder 510)
    - Life and Mission of the Church Program Emphasis
      - Papers and reports, 1958-1962 (Box 40, Folder 511)
      - LMC programs implemented by member organizations, 1958-1959 (Box 40, Folder 512)
      - Bibliographies and study guides, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 513)
      - Responsibility of the Laity for the Mission of the Church paper prepared by United Presbyterian Students, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 514)
      - Articles, 1960-1961 (Box 40, Folder 515)
      - Evaluations and reports, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 516)
      - Theme paper and cc of promotional letters to member organizations, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 517)
      - Articles, news clippings, and publications re. World, World, and Sacrament theme, 1962 (Box 40, Folder 518)
      - Galley proofs: In the Middle of the World by Howard C. Kee, 1962 (Box 40, Folder 519)
      - The Word, the World, and the Sacrament: an Interpretative Statement on the 1962-1963 Theme by Commission on Ecumenical Study and Strategy (Box 41, Folder 520)
      - Galley Proofs: Miscellaneous brochures, undated (Box 41, Folder 521)
  - Committee on Christian Work Among International Students